RICHARD HENDRIKS

PROGRAMMER

ABOUT

NEWELL ROAD PALO ALTO, CA 94303

RICHARD.HENDRIKS@PIEDPIP

(912) 555-4321

PIEDPIPER.COM 🗗

F SILICONHBO ☑

WEB DEVELOPMENT

MASTER

HTML CSS

JAVASCRIPT

COMPRESSION

MASTER

MPEG MP4 GIF

LANGUAGES

ENGLISH (NATIVE SPEAKER)

INTERESTS

WILDLIFE

Ferrets Unicorns

SUMMARY

Richard hails from Tulsa. He has earned degrees from the University of Oklahoma and Stanford. (Go Sooners and Cardinals!) Before starting Pied Piper, he worked for Hooli as a part time software developer. While his work focuses on applied information theory, mostly optimizing lossless compression schema of both the length-limited and adaptive variants, his non-work interests range widely, everything from quantum computing to chaos theory. He could tell you about it, but THAT would NOT be a "length-limited" conversation!

EXPERIENCE

PIED PIPER ☑

DECIDENT

CEO/PRESIDENT

Pied Piper is a multi-platform technology based on a proprietary universal compression algorithm that has consistently fielded high Weisman Scores™ that are not merely competitive, but approach the theoretical limit of lossless compression.

- Build an algorithm for artist to detect if their music was violating copy right infringement laws
- Successfully won Techcrunch Disrupt
- Optimized an algorithm that holds the current world record for Weisman Scores

HOOLI [☑] 01/2013 - 04/2014

SOFTWARE ENGINEER

Worked on optimizing the backend algorithms for Hooli

VOLUNTEER

CODERDOJO C 01/2012 - 01/2013

TEACHER

Global movement of free coding clubs for young people.

Awarded 'Teacher of the Month'

EDUCATION

STANFORD 06/2011 - 01/2014

PALO ALTO, CA

B.S COMPUTER SCIENCE GPA 4.0

Machine Learning

• DB1101 - Basic SQL

CS2011 - Java Introduction

AWARDS

DIGITAL COMPRESSION PIONEER AWARD

TECHCRUNCH

There is no spoon.

PUBLICATIONS

VIDEO COMPRESSION FOR 3D MEDIA ☑

10/2014

04/2014 - PRESENT

HOOL

Innovative middle-out compression algorithm that changes the way we store data.

REFERENCES

It is my pleasure to recommend Richard. That is all.